<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" > 

	<channel>
		<title>CSNSW Catholic</title>
		<atom:link href="https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au/feed/gn" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<link>https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au</link>
		<description></description>
		<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 12:11:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<language>en-AU</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod> hourly </sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency> 1 </sy:updateFrequency>
		<atom:link rel="hub" href="https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au" />

		<item>
			<title>India in South Africa: Shami to miss Test Match along with Chahar unavailable for ODIs</title>
			<link>https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au/news/sports/india-in-south-africa-shami-to-miss-test-match-along-with-chahar-unavailable-for-odis/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 12:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
						<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ruth Michaelson]]></dc:creator>			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au/?p=58</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[Shreyas Iyer, meanwhile, will leave the ODI squad after the first game to prepare for...]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Shami-miss-Test-Match-in-South-Africa.webp" class="type:primaryImage" /></figure>
<p>Shreyas Iyer, meanwhile, will leave the ODI squad after the first game to prepare for the Test series.</p>



<p>Mohammed Shami will miss the upcoming two-Test series in South Africa because of an ankle injury. Shami wasn&#8217;t part of the Test contingent that left for Johannesburg on Friday, and is currently under the watch of the BCCI&#8217;s National Cricket Academy. Deepak Chahar, meanwhile, will not be available for the ODI series in South Africa because of a &#8220;family medical emergency&#8221;.</p>



<p>While announcing the Test squad late last month, the BCCI had said that Shami was &#8220;currently undergoing medical treatment&#8221; and that his inclusion was subject to fitness. A media release on Saturday confirmed that Shami &#8220;was not cleared by BCCI&#8217;s medical team&#8221; and was subsequently withdrawn from the squad.</p>



<p>Shami last featured in a Test in June when he played the World Test Championship final against Australia. He was rested for the Caribbean tour that followed to manage his workload ahead of India&#8217;s busy white-ball season that ended with the 2023 ODI World Cup, where Shami topped the wicket-takers&#8217; chart.</p>



<p>The selectors haven&#8217;t named a replacement for Shami. Jasprit Bumrah, Mohammed Siraj, Prasidh Krishna, Mukesh Kumar and Shardul Thakur are the other fast bowlers in the touring party.</p>



<p>As for Chahar, he also missed the T20Is in South Africa last week. Chahar made his comeback during the T20Is at home against Australia last month, but featured in just one game &#8211; the fourth game in Raipur &#8211; before flying home for personal reasons.</p>



<p>Akash Deep, who was earlier part of India&#8217;s Asian Games-winning squad, has been called up into the KL Rahul-led ODI squad.</p>



<p>In another update, Shreyas Iyer will leave the squad after the first ODI in Johannesburg on December 17 to prepare for the Test matches that will follow.</p>



<p>Iyer is likely to play the intra-squad three-day fixture in the lead-up to the Boxing Day Test. His last Test was against Australia in March, after which he was sidelined with a back injury. It&#8217;s likely Iyer will reclaim his middle-order spot, which had been occupied by Ajinkya Rahane in his absence.</p>



<p>With Rahul Dravid and his team of Vikram Rathour (batting coach), Paras Mhambrey (bowling coach) and T Dilip (fielding coach) involved in preparing the Test squad for the two-match series, India&#8217;s second assignment in this WTC cycle, the ODI side will be assisted by India A&#8217;s coaching staff: Sitanshu Kotak (batting coach), Rajib Datta (bowling coach) and Ajay Ratra (fielding coach).</p>



<p>India&#8217;s updated ODI squad: Ruturaj Gaikwad, B Sai Sudharsan, Tilak Varma, Rajat Patidar, Rinku Singh, Shreyas Iyer, KL Rahul (capt, wk), Sanju Samson (wk), Axar Patel, Washington Sundar, Kuldeep Yadav, Yuzvendra Chahal, Mukesh Kumar, Avesh Khan, Arshdeep Singh, Akash Deep</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Innovative Robotics: AI-Powered Devices Transform Industries&#8221;</title>
			<link>https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au/news/tech/innovative-robotics-ai-powered-devices-transform-industries/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 12:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
						<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ruth Michaelson]]></dc:creator>			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au/?p=52</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[In 2023, the robotics industry is undergoing transformative trends that promise to reshape industrial processes....]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Innovative-Robotics.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" /></figure>
<p><br>In 2023, the robotics industry is undergoing transformative trends that promise to reshape industrial processes. Key trends include the rise of collaborative robots (#cobots) enhancing productivity, the integration of artificial intelligence (#AI) and machine learning (#ML) empowering smarter robots, the Industrial Internet of Things (#IIoT) enabling connectivity and real-time monitoring, and automation in logistics and warehousing streamlining operations. Mobile robotics, human-robot collaboration, Robot-as-a-Service (#RaaS) models, advanced sensor technologies, and the emergence of social and service robots are also driving innovation. The industry faces increased scrutiny and regulation regarding ethical and legal considerations as robotics becomes more pervasive, with a focus on ensuring safety, privacy, and ethical use. The future holds immense promise as robotics continues to play a vital role in shaping industries and daily lives.</p>



<p>Artificial intelligence (AI) and mobile robotics have advanced significantly in recent decades and the convergence of both technologies brings surprising results in several areas. Artificial intelligence robots (AI robots) are changing the way we live and work, as well as industrial processes around the world. Robotnik explores the advantages and disadvantages of AI robots. In this article, you can also find 10 examples of applications of these robots deployed in various industries.</p>



<p>WHAT ARE THE PROS AND CONS OF AI ROBOTS?<br>Pros of AI robots:<br>Improved efficiency: AI robots can continuously perform repetitive and monotonous tasks covering full shifts, increasing production efficiency and reducing labor costs.<br>Precision: they execute tasks with millimeter precision, an aspect of great relevance for sectors such as manufacturing, allowing a significant reduction in the number of errors.<br>Increased productivity: By allowing workers to focus on more creative and strategic tasks, AI robots can increase productivity and free up human resources for higher value-added work.<br>Safety: They can perform dangerous or tedious work in harsh environments, reducing risks to human workers.<br>Cons of AI robots:<br>Upfront cost: Acquiring and deploying AI robots has a cost that can be an effort, especially for SMEs or industries with tight budgets. Robotnik is working to make access to robotics more and more accessible and to eliminate these barriers to entry as much as possible.<br>Job displacement: Intelligent mobile robotics executes certain tasks more efficiently than people, so there is a natural process of work divergence in which humans move on to other types of higher-value tasks.<br>Dependency on technology: AI bots are only as effective as their programs and software, making them vulnerable to technical glitches and cyberattacks. For this reason, one of the main focuses of attention of professionals in the sector is to develop systems that are increasingly capable of protecting these devices.<br>WHAT ARE THE APPLICATIONS OF AI ROBOTS IN VARIOUS INDUSTRIES?<br>There are available examples of the interesting contribution of robots with Artificial Intelligence in a wide variety of industries, offering innovative solutions to complex problems. Here are 5 examples of AI robots:</p>



<p>Manufacturing Industry:<br>In manufacturing, AI-powered robots are used for production line automation, product assembly, quality control, and logistics. Their ability to work 24 hours a day without fatigue and with pinpoint accuracy has transformed the way consumer goods are produced.<br>Healthcare sector:<br>Have you seen real-life examples of robotic-assisted surgeries? In the same way, in the health sector, they are bringing advances for medical diagnoses and physical therapies. Their precision and ability to work in confined spaces have allowed for more precise and less invasive surgical procedures.<br>Agriculture:<br>The RB-VOGUI at Terras Gauda is an example of the application of robotics + AI for precision viticulture, whose objective is to bring together techniques for the cultivation of vines that bring competitiveness to the agri-food sector.<br>The use of mobile robotics in this area saves inspection, transport and phytosanitary costs, as well as freeing harvesters from some of the heaviest parts of the process.<br>Automotive:<br>In the automotive industry, AI-powered robots are particularly well-suited for vehicle manufacturing tasks, from body welding to painting and assembly. This use case describes the intralogistics automation process in an automotive plant with a collaborative AMR from Robotnik.<br>Services &amp; Hospitality:<br>There are robots such as PLATO, from United Robotics Group, which have been developed specifically to operate in sectors such as hospitality and customer service in reception, cleaning or food service tasks. These robots, combined with Artificial Intelligence technology, not only reduce labor costs but also improve the customer experience.</p>



<p>WHAT ARE AI ROBOTS USED FOR?<br>These robots are used in a wide range of applications, some of which are mentioned in the previous section. 5 other uses of robots with Artificial Intelligence that you may not know about:</p>



<p>Security and defense: AI robots are used in military and security applications for tasks such as explosive ordnance disposal, surveillance, and patrolling high-risk areas.<br>Scientific research: These systems are valuable tools in scientific research, aiding in data collection in areas such as oceanography, climatology, and marine biology.<br>Inspection and Maintenance: In hazardous or hard-to-reach environments such as oil rigs, electrical substations or nuclear facilities, robots are used for inspection and maintenance tasks, reducing risks to human workers.<br>Domestic services: The most democratized AI robots are those used in the home for tasks such as cleaning (e.g., robot vacuum cleaners), lighting and temperature management, or assistance in the kitchen.<br>Last-mile delivery and logistics: Autonomous ground-based robots and AI drones for parcel and food delivery in urban areas are one of the growing trends within the mobile robotics sector to improve the efficiency of last-mile logistics.<br>Check out this interview with Roberto Guzmán, CEO of Robotnik, talking about last-mile robotics, robotics and Artificial Intelligence and other disruptive topics.</p>



<p>CONCLUSION<br>AI robots are transforming industries around the world by offering improved efficiency, accuracy, and safety in a variety of applications. Although there are challenges such as initial investment or the lack of a stable regulatory framework, its potential to improve people’s working conditions and improvements in the efficiency of processes is indisputable. As technology advances, expect an increase in the applications they are capable of running. The future is already here and robots that integrate Artificial Intelligence algorithms are leading the way towards a new era of automation and innovation that involves most industrial sectors.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Global Summit Addresses Urgent Climate Crisis</title>
			<link>https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au/news/global-summit-addresses-urgent-climate-crisis/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 11:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
						<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ruth Michaelson]]></dc:creator>			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au/?p=42</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[Global leaders at the UN climate summit in Dubai reached a historic agreement, calling for...]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Global-Summit.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" /></figure>
<p>Global leaders at the UN climate summit in Dubai reached a historic agreement, calling for all nations to transition away from fossil fuels to curb greenhouse gas emissions and limit global warming. While the agreement fell short of explicitly demanding a fossil fuel phase-out, it marked a significant shift in climate diplomacy, acknowledging the urgency of deep emissions reductions. The first Global Stocktake revealed that current emission reduction commitments are insufficient to meet the 1.5°C warming target. The WWF welcomed the transition away from fossil fuels but urged increased ambition and implementation of climate action, emphasizing the need for renewable energy transformation.</p>



<p>After days of intense negotiations, a landmark agreement emerged from the UN climate summit in Dubai, marking a significant step towards addressing the climate crisis.</p>



<p>For the first time in history, the agreement explicitly calls on all nations to transition away from fossil fuels, a crucial step in curbing greenhouse gas emissions and limiting global warming.</p>



<p>While the agreement stopped short of explicitly calling for a phase-out of fossil fuels, a move that many governments had hoped for, its acknowledgment of the need to move away from these polluting energy sources represents a significant shift in global climate diplomacy.</p>



<p>The text clearly recognizes the urgency of the situation, stating that &#8220;deep, rapid and sustained reductions&#8221; in emissions are essential to avoid the devastating consequences of exceeding the 1.5°C warming threshold set out by the Paris Agreement.</p>



<p>This newfound recognition of the need to transition away from fossil fuels is a testament to the growing global consensus on the urgency of the climate crisis.</p>



<p>It is a sign that even in the face of immense challenges and vested interests, nations are able to come together to address this existential threat. Now countries must turn this agreement into action.</p>



<p>This will require a significant scale up of climate finance to unlock this action.</p>



<p>Developed countries must deliver the finance needed to ensure all countries can rapidly decarbonise and restore nature.</p>



<p>Despite these challenges, the agreement reached at COP28 is a step in the right direction, signaling a willingness among nations to recognize the gravity of the situation and take action to address it.</p>



<p>The first global stocktake revealed we&#8217;re off track<br>The world is not on track to meet the goal of limiting rising temperatures to 1.5°C, above pre-industrial levels. This was the stark conclusion of the first Global Stocktake (GST), conducted at COP28, the 28th Conference of the Parties to the UN Framework Convention on Climate Change.</p>



<p>The GST, a comprehensive assessment of global climate action, found that current national commitments to reduce greenhouse gas emissions are woefully inadequate.</p>



<p>To stay within the 1.5°C warming target, global emissions need to be cut by 42% below 2010 levels by 2030. However, current NDCs put us on track for only a 14% reduction.</p>



<p>The GST served as a sobering reminder of the urgency of climate action.</p>



<p>The world is rapidly approaching the point of no return, and we need to take immediate and drastic action to avert the worst impacts of climate change.</p>



<p>The GST outcome is a call to action for all countries, businesses, and individuals to step up their efforts and work together to achieve a sustainable future.</p>



<p>What is WWF’s assessment?<br>WWF welcomes the decision by countries to transition away from fossil fuels, but is disappointed at the failure to commit to a full phase out.</p>



<p>WWF calls for increased ambition and implementation of climate action, highlighting the need to transform energy systems and replace fossil fuels with clean and cheaper renewable energy at an unprecedented speed and scale.</p>



<p>The WWF also calls for more funding to help people in harm&#8217;s way and for action to protect nature.</p>



<p>World leaders called on Friday for urgent action to slow global warming as the annual United Nations climate summit kicked into gear against a backdrop of two major wars and rising global temperatures.</p>



<p>King Charles III challenged the gathering in Dubai to take “genuine transformational action” to slow the spiral of greenhouse gas emissions, and the United Nations secretary general, António Guterres, called for the total phase-out of fossil fuels, on the second day of the meeting, known as COP28.</p>



<p>Other heads of state and government will speak on Saturday and the event will continue for 10 days as negotiators from nearly every nation try to find common cause in the fight against climate change.</p>



<p>The meeting comes toward the end of what will almost certainly be the hottest year in recorded history. Greenhouse gas emissions, mainly driven by the burning of fossil fuels, have now warmed the planet by about 1.2 degrees Celsius above preindustrial levels. Floods, fires, droughts and storms made worse by climate change are unleashing destruction around the world.</p>



<p>The leaders calling for swift action to reduce emissions face a daunting task. While many developed countries are installing more wind and solar power, global greenhouse gas emissions and fossil fuel demand continue to rise.</p>



<p>Any final agreement must be ratified by every country in attendance. The need for unanimous consent means that each word in the final document will be scrutinized. In previous years, representatives from oil producing nations have vetoed language calling for a rapid phaseout of fossil fuels.</p>



<p>Here’s what else to know:</p>



<p>The summit officially opened Thursday with delegates reaching an agreement in principle on a fund that will help poor countries cope with climate disasters. Another big issue on the table at the meeting is an international effort to limit emissions of methane, a potent greenhouse gas.</p>



<p>Speaking Friday, India’s prime minister, Narendra Modi, rebuked developed nations for “indiscriminately” exploiting the planet and pledged to redouble his nation’s shift away from fossil fuels.</p>



<p>The meeting has drawn criticism for the heavy presence of oil and gas executives. The oil-rich host nation, the United Arab Emirates, has been accused of trying to strike oil deals on the sidelines of the summit. The president of the proceedings, Sultan Al Jaber, is the head of the Emirates’ state oil company, Adnoc. In his opening remarks on Thursday, Mr. Al Jaber defended the presence of fossil fuel interests at COP28, saying: “Let history reflect the fact that this is the presidency that made a bold choice to proactively engage with oil and gas companies.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Fintech Breakthrough: Digital Currency Gains Traction in Mainstream Finance</title>
			<link>https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au/news/business/fintech-breakthrough-digital-currency-gains-traction-in-mainstream-finance/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 11:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
						<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ruth Michaelson]]></dc:creator>			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au/?p=49</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[As the financial sector undergoes a &#8220;reset&#8221; post-pandemic, fintech is becoming a mainstream player. China,...]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Fintech-Breakthrough.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" /></figure>
<p>As the financial sector undergoes a &#8220;reset&#8221; post-pandemic, fintech is becoming a mainstream player. China, particularly, emphasizes fintech in its financial development plans, with the People&#8217;s Bank of China focusing on a new three-year fintech development plan. Key findings from KPMG&#8217;s &#8220;China Leading Fintech 50 and Future 50&#8221; report show that fintech concentration remains high in cities like Beijing, Shanghai, and Shenzhen. Blockchain is increasingly cited as a core technology, rising to 49% in 2021 from 34% in 2020. The digital yuan&#8217;s pilot program is expanding, with potential applications in the digital economy, payment systems, and cross-border transactions. Supply chain finance and digital acceleration, particularly through blockchain, are highlighted as pivotal in addressing challenges and promoting stable supply chain development. The report underscores the importance of fintech in enhancing market efficiency and allocating resources effectively in the real economy.</p>



<p>As the financial sector ‘resets’ following the pandemic, fintech is already moving into the mainstream.</p>



<p>Amid the COVID-19 pandemic, commentaries on finance have been peppered with the word “reset”, followed by an incredibly wide range of proposals as to what this “reset” may entail.</p>



<p>One common theme has been that financial technology will play a key role in the sector going forward. Mainland China strongly emphasises fintech in its financial development plan, and the central People’s Bank of China is running three-year fintech development plans. The 2019-2021 plan has just finished and the bank is now moving into the 2022-2025 plan.</p>



<p>The new plan seeks to further develop the mainland’s fintech sector and drive the economy’s digital transformation of finance over the next four years. The fintech development plan is based on the mainland’s 14th Five Year Plan, a roadmap for social and economic development between 2021 and 2025.</p>



<p>Global business services firm KPMG recently released its 2021 “China Leading Fintech 50 and Future 50” report, looking at the leading firms in the sector, giving an overview of the industry and discussing trends and prospects.</p>



<p>Cluster-based development<br>The KMPG study found that leading fintechs are heavily concentrated in three cities. Beijing (27%), Shanghai (25%) and Shenzhen (23%) remain at the top of the list, demonstrating a strong clustering effect. The big-three’s cumulative 75% fell seven percentage points from 2020 as other big cities such as Hangzhou and Chengdu become more attractive in the eyes of promising fintech enterprises.</p>



<p>Geographically, the study revealed that almost all enterprises are in the top city clusters earmarked for priority development in the 14th Five-Year Plan – the Yangtze River Delta (35%), Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area (29%), Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei (27%) and Chengdu-Chongqing (7%).</p>



<p>The ABCD technologies (artificial intelligence, blockchain, cloud computing and big data) remain core technologies for fintech enterprises. The percentage of companies that cited blockchain as a core technology rose to 49% in 2021, compared with 34% in 2020, as richer blockchain scenarios in finance attracted more attention to blockchain development during the year.</p>



<p>As the digital yuan pilot programme expands, user and transaction volumes have steadily increased, the study found. Following its official launch, the digital yuan will promote the development of the mainland’s digital economy, reshape the payment system, and help the central bank apply measures across various scenarios at the government, business and consumer levels.</p>



<p>KPMG also expected the digital yuan to boost innovation, provide important infrastructure for fintech companies and open up business opportunities for commercial banks and other financial institutions related to digital transformation. The digital yuan use may be extended to foreign exchange management and cross-border payments, as well being applied to the agriculture, education and urban construction sectors.</p>



<p>In the mainland, fintech’s steady progress has reduced the cost of financial services, and the development of big data, blockchain and other technologies has given rise to more secure and convenient payment methods like the digital yuan, while also lending solid technical support to development of the financial sector, KPMG said.</p>



<p>Top-50 selection<br>KPMG chose firms for its top 50 list based on innovation and transformation, popularisation of financial services, industry development prospects, capital market recognition, technology and data.</p>



<p>KPMG developed a start-up insights platform (SIP) model, which combines these core dimensions to evaluate enterprises from multiple dimensions including collaboration, technology, product, market and financing.</p>



<p>Platform technology empowerment (31% of selected companies) and wealthtech enterprises (17%) ranked first and second among selected firms in 2021, followed by inclusive technology and insurtech (both 13%). To highlight how fintech is returning to the basics of technological services, platform technology empowerment was divided into four sub-segments – integrated technology empowerment (6%); big data and AI (11%); blockchain, privacy computing and security (10%); and distributed computing, cloud computing and hardware acceleration (4%).</p>



<p>KPMG said finance is the lifeblood of the mainland economy, but the real economy is the ultimate driver of financial-sector development. Fintech, in the most basic sense, uses innovation to break two major pain points – information mismatch and high transaction costs – and promotes the development of the real economy, consumption and industrial upgrading.</p>



<p>In recent years, fintech development has boomed as new business models and scenarios have emerged. However, at the end of the day, fintech still aims to enhance market efficiency and rationally allocate resources.</p>



<p>Supply chain solutions<br>The global COVID-19 outbreak and regulatory changes presented significant challenges to global supply chains, and some domestic enterprises have even been forced to shut down for the time being. In this context, supply chain finance is playing a pivotal role in resolving the financing difficulties of micro, small and medium-sized enterprises and promoting stable supply chain development.</p>



<p>Historically, supply chain finance has been plagued by challenges, including large numbers of participants, interrelated participants and processes, and difficulties related to the identification of transaction scenarios. To address these issues, blockchain and electronic certificates can be used to connect supply chain participants and establish an alliance that includes upstream and downstream entities, finance companies, financial institutions, banks and other trade finance participants, the study report said.</p>



<p>Enterprises can use these technologies to digitalise assets such as accounts receivable, bills and warehouse receipts, and credit can then be granted to suppliers at different levels of the supply chain. In this way, blockchain can reduce financing costs and enhance capital efficiency across the entire supply chain.</p>



<p>Digital acceleration</p>



<p>Honson To, Chairman of KPMG China and Asia Pacific, said that based on the guidance provided by the development plan, during the past three years, the “four beams and eight columns” of fintech had been formed and the digital transformation of the financial sector had accelerated.</p>



<p>“2022 marks the sixth consecutive year in which KPMG has published the China Fintech 50. During this time, we have been pleased to witness the growth of so many outstanding fintech players. Going forward, we sincerely hope that the fintech industry will build an open, sustainable, scenario-based ecosystem under the guidance of national strategies that promote both prudent regulation and innovation.”</p>



<p>Jacky Zou, Vice Chairman and Senior Partner, Northern Region, KPMG China said new business models and scenarios had led to a fintech boom.</p>



<p>“The industry needs to focus on the essence of technological services and use technologies to break through the pain-points of traditional financial services,” he said. “The digital ABCD technologies were remaking great progress and have laid the foundation for the development of fintech infrastructure.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Global Trade Dynamics Shift as New Trade Agreement Takes Effect</title>
			<link>https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au/news/business/global-trade-dynamics-shift-as-new-trade-agreement-takes-effect/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 12:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
						<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ruth Michaelson]]></dc:creator>			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au/?p=55</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[The author, reflecting on their tenure as the US trade representative in 2013, discusses the...]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Global-Trade-Dynamics-Shift.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" /></figure>
<p>The author, reflecting on their tenure as the US trade representative in 2013, discusses the evolving landscape of global trade and the need for a reenvisioned framework. The convergence of climate and trade policies, exemplified by the Inflation Reduction Act (IRA) in the US and the Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM) in the European Union (EU), raises questions about collaboration or conflicts between major economies. The author argues that the World Trade Organization (WTO) faces challenges in resolving such issues and suggests a substantive conversation among leaders to address fundamental questions about the global trading system&#8217;s focus, role, and standards. Open plurilateralism is proposed as a promising way to advance trade issues in the absence of consensus around multilateral agreements. The author emphasizes the importance of addressing the complexities of the global trading system and the need for successful solutions.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s time to reenvision the global trade framework for a sustainable future</p>



<p>When I became the US trade representative in 2013, my then-11-year-old son asked me to explain my new job. He had accompanied me on a trip to India the year before, and we had visited the US ambassador at his beautiful residence in Delhi. My son understood that as trade representative, people called me “Ambassador” too, but we weren’t moving to a new country and new house. He was curious. “What the heck does a trade representative do anyway?” he asked.</p>



<p>I suggested we look at the labels on the clothes in his closet. Made in Mexico. Made in Bangladesh. Made in Cambodia. “All of them,” I explained, “represent a trade agreement or a trade preference program that countries negotiated. It all comes down to trade,” I told him.</p>



<p>In the decade since, global trade has taken some significant twists and turns. Trade agreements and globalization were once lauded for creating efficient and dynamic supply chains, lifting hundreds of millions of people out of poverty, and reducing prices for consumers around the globe. What followed has been a sharp backlash amid concerns that trade liberalization and the offshoring of manufacturing had hollowed out industry in developed nations. Countries are now pursuing more nationalistic policies. And in turn, that has led to hand-wringing about the future of the multilateral trading system and, specifically, the role of the World Trade Organization (WTO).</p>



<p>While globalization is being intensely scrutinized, it is also evolving. Rumors of its death are largely exaggerated or, at least, are premature. Some countries have certainly retreated from negotiations to liberalize trade, but others, particularly in Africa, continue to charge ahead. Companies are reevaluating their supply chains, focusing not solely on efficiency, but also on security, resilience, and redundancies. There has been some onshoring, but also nearshoring and even friend-shoring. Global trade continues to grow.</p>



<p>At the same time, the global trading system has reached an inflection point. Pressing concerns, such as the convergence of climate and trade policies, could strengthen international cooperation or create new fissures. And there are real questions about the limits of multilateralism and the need for a new political consensus around trade.</p>



<p>Convergence of climate and trade<br>Late last year, I was in Egypt for COP27, the UN’s climate change conference. The dialogue was one of urgency. Governments, environmentalists, scientists, and business executives all focused on what could be done to address global warming.</p>



<p>The conference itself produced modest results, but, looking back, the most ambitious climate change actions might well have been unilateral steps taken by major economies last year—specifically the Inflation Reduction Act (IRA) in the US and the Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM) in the European Union (EU).</p>



<p>The IRA became law last August and is considered one of the most significant pieces of climate legislation ever enacted in the US. It includes $400 billion in climate-related spending over a decade. Among other things, it incentivizes electric vehicle purchases with a $7,500 consumer tax credit, and it subsidizes US-based manufacturers to produce clean tech and green energy.</p>



<p>The CBAM, which goes into effect in October, will impose a fee—the EU is careful not to talk about it as a tariff or a tax—on imported products from manufacturers in countries that do not have comparable carbon pricing mechanisms.</p>



<p>The IRA has faced criticism from US non-free-trade-agreement partners. They argue that applying these subsidies is discriminatory and could lead to the outflow of clean-energy-related investments from other countries. This, in turn, has led the EU to propose an additional package of clean energy subsidies of its own. The CBAM has raised concerns that, given the complexity of measuring emissions and comparing carbon pricing mechanisms, the EU’s unilateral judgments could be exploited for protectionist purposes, including against developing economies.</p>



<p>While climate and trade policies once operated as separate regimes, they are now converging, and sometimes conflicting. Whether major economies collaborate or go their own way is yet to be determined.</p>



<p>Trend toward open plurilateralism<br>Can the WTO resolve an issue like this? Likely not, at least not in the short term. Since its founding in 1995, the WTO has been slow or unable to fully reach multilateral agreements, with the notable exceptions of the Trade Facilitation and the Fisheries Subsidies agreements, two leading multilateral deals.</p>



<p>While trade economists tell us that multilateral agreements are the highest and best form of trade liberalization, our collective experience in recent decades has made clear that there is no political consensus around what major economies want from the global trading system and what role the WTO should play. Indeed, it is hard to achieve institutional reform if there is no underlying political consensus.</p>



<p>What is needed now is a substantive conversation among leaders of major economies about the shifting and often contradictory demands on the global trading system. To what degree should it be focused on economic efficiency? On national industrial agendas? On economic development? To what degree should it address labor and environmental issues? What role should it play in leveling the playing field, disciplining state-owned enterprises, and weighing subsidies? Ultimately, should the goal be creating a rules-based system and the mechanisms for enforcing those rules?</p>



<p>These are fundamental questions that need to be addressed before meaningful WTO reform can be achieved. And they cannot be answered by simply ignoring or wishing away the reality of democracies, domestic politics, or public opinion. Populism, nationalism, nativism, and protectionism are real. They shouldn’t dictate a lowest-common-denominator economic policy, but they do need to be addressed.</p>



<p>In the meantime, in the absence of consensus around the global trading system, the world continues to spin on its axis, technology advances, and economies evolve. Now, more than ever, coalitions need to come together to set standards that can lay the groundwork for a broader approach.</p>



<p>Take the digital economy. Issues around the role of digital services, data, privacy, and cybersecurity, to name a few, have a potentially greater impact on many economies than tariffs.</p>



<p>Disciplines that were introduced in previous regional and bilateral trade agreements set high standards around some of the most important issues facing the global economy. Now, too, there is an opportunity for public and private sectors to collaborate, but there is also a risk that unilateral action by one party or another could lead to greater trade friction.</p>



<p>In the absence of consensus around multilateral agreements, open plurilateralism—the negotiation of agreements among countries willing to go above and beyond the lowest common denominator and willing to live up to those standards—might well be the most promising way to advance important trade issues. A series of recent trade deals, from the Comprehensive and Progressive Agreement for Trans-Pacific Partnership to the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement, are important examples of how to move forward.</p>



<p>The importance of getting it right<br>The challenges facing the global trading system might have gotten more complex since the journey through my son’s closet a decade ago, but it is more important than ever that we deal with those challenges successfully. There is too much at stake to be complacent.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Gaming Trends: The Rise of Esports and Virtual Communities</title>
			<link>https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au/news/lifestyle-entertainment/gaming-trends-the-rise-of-esports-and-virtual-communities/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 11:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
						<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ruth Michaelson]]></dc:creator>			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au/?p=46</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[The surge in gaming and eSports has transformed the once-recreational hobby into a thriving industry....]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://cdn.csnsw.catholic.edu.au/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Gaming-Trends.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" /></figure>
<p>The surge in gaming and eSports has transformed the once-recreational hobby into a thriving industry. eSports, organized video game competitions, feature popular titles like League of Legends and Fortnite, drawing millions of global viewers and offering substantial prize pools. The growth has spawned professional gaming careers, with players earning income through tournaments, sponsorships, and streaming. Platforms like Twitch and YouTube Gaming facilitate live streaming, enabling gamers to connect with audiences, showcase skills, and generate revenue. Gaming has evolved into a social experience, fostering virtual communities and friendships. The rise of eSports has led to dedicated infrastructure, increased spectatorship, and integration with traditional sports, making gaming a significant part of mainstream entertainment and culture.</p>



<p>Gaming and eSports have experienced a significant rise in popularity, transforming gaming from a recreational hobby into a thriving industry. The emergence of competitive gaming and virtual communities has revolutionized the way people engage with games and connect with fellow gamers. Here’s an overview of the trends and impact of gaming and eSports:</p>



<ol>
<li>Competitive Gaming (eSports): eSports refers to organized video game competitions where professional gamers or teams compete against each other in various game genres. eSports events are held at both the amateur and professional levels, with tournaments featuring popular games like League of Legends, Dota 2, Counter-Strike: Global Offensive, and Fortnite. These events attract millions of viewers worldwide, with dedicated eSports leagues and organizations offering substantial prize pools.</li>



<li>Professional Gaming Careers: The growth of eSports has created opportunities for individuals to pursue professional gaming careers. Professional gamers can earn substantial incomes through tournament winnings, sponsorship deals, streaming revenue, and merchandise sales. This has led to the establishment of eSports teams, player contracts, and dedicated training facilities, similar to traditional sports organizations.</li>



<li>Live Streaming and Content Creation: Live streaming platforms such as Twitch and YouTube Gaming have played a crucial role in the growth of gaming and eSports. Gamers can broadcast their gameplay, engage with viewers through live chat, and build communities around their content. Streaming has become a popular form of entertainment, allowing gamers to showcase their skills, entertain audiences, and generate revenue through subscriptions, donations, and ad revenue.</li>



<li>Virtual Communities and Social Interaction: Gaming has become a social experience, with virtual communities forming around specific games, genres, and platforms. Online multiplayer games and eSports tournaments provide opportunities for players to connect, collaborate, and compete with others from around the world. Virtual communities foster friendships, teamwork, and a sense of belonging, with players forming clans, guilds, or online communities centered around shared interests.</li>



<li>Professional eSports Infrastructure: The growth of eSports has led to the development of professional infrastructure and support systems. This includes dedicated eSports arenas, training facilities, coaching staff, and talent agencies representing professional gamers. Major sports organizations and franchises have also entered the eSports arena, investing in teams and creating cross-industry partnerships.</li>



<li>Spectatorship and Fan Engagement: eSports events have gained immense popularity, attracting millions of spectators both in-person and online. Major tournaments are broadcasted on streaming platforms and traditional media channels, with viewership rivalling that of traditional sports events. Spectators engage through live chat, social media, and online forums, creating a sense of community and camaraderie among fans.</li>



<li>Gaming as a Spectator Sport: The growth of eSports has transformed gaming into a spectator sport. Large-scale eSports events are held in arenas, where fans gather to watch professional gamers compete on big screens. The rise of virtual reality (VR) and augmented reality (AR) technologies may further enhance the spectator experience, offering immersive views and interactive elements during live events.</li>



<li>Integration of Traditional Sports and Gaming: Traditional sports organizations have recognized the potential of gaming and eSports, leading to collaborations and crossover events. Sports franchises have created eSports teams, and professional athletes have become involved in gaming and streaming. This convergence allows for cross-promotion, increased fan engagement, and the blending of physical and virtual sports experiences.</li>
</ol>



<p>The rise of competitive gaming and virtual communities has had a profound impact on the gaming industry and popular culture. Gaming is no longer limited to individual players; it has evolved into a social and competitive experience, fostering a global community of gamers and enthusiasts. As technology advances and the popularity of eSports continues to grow, gaming and eSports are likely to become even more integrated into mainstream entertainment and sporting culture.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
<!-- last GN Pub feeds fetch (not specifically this feed): has not fetched -->
